Harold Willard Gleason Papers
Harold Willard Gleason Papers
1909-1966
Gleason, Harold Willard.
2.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet (1895-1975).
Correspondence (1916-1964); holograph, typescript, and published poems; articles and photographs.
149005
Biographical History
Harold Willard Gleason (1895-??) was an American poet and teacher.
Born July 31, 1895, he was educated in Boston Latin School, Harvard, and Trinity College, Hartford, Connecticut. From 1917-1946 he taught in the English Department at Kingswood School in West Hartford, Connecticut, and served as head of the department from 1923-1946.
Gleason was an instructor in verse, Maine Writers' Conference in 1953-1957. He was a member of the Classical Association of New England, Poetry Society of America, Poetry Fellowship of Maine, and the Sons of the American Revolution.
A variety of his works have appeared in the Anthology of Kingswood Verse. At least ninety national magazines and newspapers have published his works, among them The New Yorker, Poetry, New York Times, American Mercury, Coronet, Good Housekeeping, and the Saturday Evening Post.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Harold Gleason Papers consists of correspondence, subject files, and manuscripts of poems. The latter spans more than forty years.
Arrangement of the Collection
Outgoing correspondence is arranged chronologically, incoming alphabetically. Subject files are arranged alphabetically. Manuscripts are in chronological order by year.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Gleason, Harold Willard -- Archives.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Poets, American.; Articles.; Correspondence.; Photographs.; Poems.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing, 1947-1963; undated (Box 1)
  - Incoming
    - Allen - Harding, 1926-1964; undated (Box 1)
    - Harvard - Keyes, F.P., 1916-1962; undated (Box 1)
    - Knauss - Shipman, 1923-1959 (Box 1)
- Subject file
  - Singer Co. - Youth's Companion and miscellaneous, 1915-1962; undated (Box 1)
  - Biographical Material (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Magazine and Newspaper Articles (Box 1)
  - Gleason, H.W. (ed.) An Anthology of Kingswood Verse (West Hartford, Conn. 1946) and a typescript note from M r. Gleason (Box 1)
- Manuscripts
  - Holograph poems (original drafts), undated (Box 1)
  - "Children's poems" before, 1923-1938; undated (Box 1)
  - "Sea Verse", 1922-1950 (Box 1)
  - "Shaggerty Blue Saga poems", 1928-1930; undated (Box 1)
  - "'Western Verse" poems, 1924-1953; undated (Box 1)
  - "World War I" poems, 1918 (Box 1)
  - Typescript poems, 1936-1964 (Box 1)
  - Published Copies of poems, 1916-1953; undated (Box 1)
  - Typescript poem (Box 1)
  - Poems, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Typescript poem, 1913 (Box 1)
  - "Nostalgic Notes" (Boston Latin School 1913) (Box 1)
  - Typescript poems, 1915-1916; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Typescript poems, 1918 (Box 1)
  - Poems, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Typescript poems, 1920-1922; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Poems, 1923-1924; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Typescript poems, 1924-1927; 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Poems, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Typescript poems, 1929; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Poems Published, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Poems Published, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Poems Published, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Poems, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Typescript poems, 1932-1934; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Poems, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Typescript poems, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Poems, 1937 (Box 2)
  - "To the Class of 1937" Kingswood School, undated (Box 2)
  - Typescript poems, 1938-1943; 8 folders (Box 2)
  - Poems, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Typescript poems, 1945-1947; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Poems, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Typescript poems, 1949-1964; 15 folders (Box 2)
  - Poems, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Typescript poems, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Poems, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Typescript poems, undated (Box 2)
  - Typescript poems Before, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Typescript poems 193? (Box 2)
  - Poems, 1930 (Box 2)